Preliminary Guide to the Yale Repertory Theatre Scripts Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Yale Repertory Theatre Scripts Collection
1966-2009
DRA 30
Yale University Arts Library
57.55
(138 boxes)
The collection consists of scripts from plays produced by the Yale Repertory Theatre. Individual records for these scripts are also available in Orbis.
Yale Repertory Theatre
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Repertory Theatre Scripts Collection was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of scripts from plays produced by the Yale Repertory Theatre. Individual records for these scripts are also available in Orbis.
Arrangement
Scripts are arranged chronologically by year of production, then alphabetically by author's last name.
Repertory theater; Scripts (documents); Yale Repertory Theatre
- Yale Repertory Theatre Scripts
  Arrangement
  Scripts are arranged chronologically by year of production, then alphabetically by author's last name.
  - Prometheus Bound, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Volpone, 1966-1967 (Box 123)
  - Viet Rock, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1966-1967 (Box 123)
  - Three Sisters, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Three Sisters, 1967-1968 (Box 123)
  - Tis a Pity She's a Whore, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - We Bombed in New Haven, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Henry IV, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Coriolanus, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Saved, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Photo Contact Sheets for Saved, They Told Me You Came This Way, and The Great Chinese Revolution, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - They Told Me That You Came This Way, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - The Bacchae, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - God Bless, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - The Great Chinese Revolution, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - Greatshot, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - The Government Inspector, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Don Juan, or The Enemy of God, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Ovid's Metamorphoses [aka Olympian Games], 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - The Rivals, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - The Rivals, 1969-1970 (Box 123)
  - Crimes and Crimes, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Transformations (The Rhesus Umbrella; Clutch; Iz She Izzy), 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Ikke, Ikke, Nye, Nye, Nye, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Play, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - The Little Mahagonny, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Woyzeck, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Julian the Hospitaler, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Where Has Tommy Flowers Gone?, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Macbeth, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Gimpel the Fool, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Production Book for Gimpel the Fool, Julian the Hospitaler, and Ovid's Metamorphoses, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - The Revenger's Tragedy, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Stops, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Are You Now or Have You Ever Been?, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Lear, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Baal, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - A Cabal of Hypocrites (aka Monsieur de Moliere), 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - The American War Mothers (Sunday Reading Series), 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Macbett, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - The Bourgeois Gentleman, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - A Break in the Skin, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - In the Clap Shack, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - The War Show, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - The Mirror, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Pornography Show, 1972-1973 (Box 124)
  - The Frogs, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - The Frogs, 1973-1974 (Box 124)
  - The Rise and Fall of the City of Mahagonny, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Watergate Classics, 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Dark Room, 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - And Evening with Dead Essex, 1973-1974 (Box 16)
  - Three Plays (Sunday Reading Series), 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - The Tubs, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - The Tempest, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Geography of a Horse Dreamer, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Schlemiel the First, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Happy End, 1974-1975 (Box 19)
  - Victory, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
  - The Shaft of Love, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
  - The Possessed, 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  - The Idiots Karamazov, 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  - The Father, 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  - Walk the Dog, Willie, 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - From the Memoirs of Pontius Pilate (Sunday Reading Series), 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Bingo, 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Trade-Offs, 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - General Gorgeous, 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Don Juan, 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1975-1976 (Box 124)
  - Troilus and Cressida, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Man Fly (Sunday Reading Series), 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1975-1976 (Box 27)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Dynamite Tonite, 1975-1976 (Box 125)
  - Mississippi Mud, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - Puntila, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - Puntila, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - Ivanov, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - The Vietnamization of New Jersey, 1976-1977 (Box 31)
  - The Durango Flash, 1976-1977 (Box 31)
  - The Durango Flash, 1976-1977 (Box 32)
  - The Woods, 1976-1977 (Box 32)
  - White Marriage, 1976-1977 (Box 33)
  - The Banquet Years, 1976-1977 (Box 33)
  - The Banquet Years, 1976-1977 (Box 138)
  - Julius Caesar, 1976-1977 (Box 33)
  - Suicide in B-flat, 1976-1977 (Box 34)
  - Ha Ha (Sunday Reading Series), 1977-1978 (Box 34)
  - Man is Man, 1977-1978 (Box 35)
  - Wild Duck, 1977-1978 (Box 36)
  - Wings, 1977-1978 (Box 37)
  - Reunion/Dark Pony, 1977-1978 (Box 37)
  - Forced Marriage, 1977-1978 (Box 38)
  - Sganarelle, 1977-1978 (Box 38)
  - We're on the One Road, 1977-1978 (Box 38)
  - Ghost Sonata, 1977-1978 (Box 38)
  - Terra Nov a (Includes the early draft " Heart in the Ice "), 1977-1978 (Box 39)
  - Mistaken Identities (Includes 'Dentity Crisis and Guess Work ), 1978-1979 (Box 40)
  - The Bundle, 1978-1979 (Box 41)
  - Mahagonny, 1978-1979 (Box 42)
  - Mahagonny, 1978-1979 (Box 125)
  - End of the War (Sunday Series), 1978-1979 (Box 42)
  - The Sea Gull, 1978-1979 (Box 42)
  - Eden Cinema (Sunday Series), 1978-1979 (Box 126)
  - Tales From the Vienna Woods, 1978-1979 (Box 43)
  - Deathbed Follies (Sunday Series), 1978-1979 (Box 44)
  - As You Like It, 1978-1979 (Box 44)
  - As You Like It, 1978-1979 (Box 126)
  - Buried Child, 1978-1979 (Box 44)
  - A Lesson from Aloes, 1979-1980 (Box 45)
  - Bosoms and Neglect, 1979-1980 (Box 45)
  - They Are Dying Out, 1979-1980 (Box 46)
  - Ubu Rex, 1979-1980 (Box 46)
  - Ubu Rex, 1979-1980 (Box 127)
  - Measure for Measure, 1979-1980 (Box 46)
  - Timon of Athens, 1979-1980 (Box 47)
  - Timon of Athens, 1979-1980 (Box 127)
  - Curse of the Starving Class, 1979-1980 (Box 47)
  - The Magnificent Cuckold, 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - The Suicide, 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - Boseman and Lena, 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - Hedda Gabler, 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - Domestic Issues, 1980-1981 (Box 48)
  - Rococo, 1980-1981 (Box 49)
  - The Resurrection of Lady Lester, 1980-1981 (Box 49)
  - Sally and Marsha, 1980-1981 (Box 50)
  - An Attempt at Flying, 1980-1981 (Box 50)
  - An Attempt at Flying, 1980-1981 (Box 127)
  - Twelfth Night, 1980-1981 (Box 51)
  - Johnny Bull, 1981-1982 (Box 51)
  - Going Over, 1981-1982 (Box 52)
  - Uncle Vanya, 1981-1982 (Box 52)
  - Flash Floods, 1981-1982 (Box 53)
  - Master Harold….and the boys, 1981-1982 (Box 53)
  - Rip Van Winkle, 1981-1982 (Box 54)
  - Love's Labors Lost, 1981-1982 (Box 55)
  - Mrs. Warren's Profession, 1981-1982 (Box 56)
  - Beef, No Chicken, 1981-1982 (Box 56)
  - The Man Who Could See Through Time, 1981-1982 (Box 56)
  - About Face, 1982-1983 (Box 57)
  - Hello and Goodbye, 1982-1983 (Box 57)
  - Playing in Local Bands, 1982-1983 (Box 57)
  - A Doll House, 1982-1983 (Box 58)
  - Astapovo, 1982-1983 (Box 58)
  - A Touch of the Poet, 1982-1983 (Box 59)
  - The Philanderer, 1982-1983 (Box 59)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1982-1983 (Box 59)
  - Richard II, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
  - Coyote Ugly, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
  - Chopin in Space, 1983-1984 (Box 61)
  - The Day of the Picnic, 1983-1984 (Box 61)
  - The Road to Mecca, 1983-1984 (Box 61)
  - A Raisin in the Sun, 1983-1984 (Box 62)
  - Night is the Mother to Day, 1983-1984 (Box 62)
  - The Sweet Life, 1983-1984 (Box 63)
  - Major Barbara, 1983-1984 (Box 64)
  - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, 1983-1984 (Box 64)
  - Vampires in Kodachrome, 1984-1985 (Box 65)
  - Faulkner's Bicycle, 1984-1985 (Box 65)
  - Tartuffe, 1984-1985 (Box 66)
  - Between East and West, 1984-1985 (Box 66)
  - What the Butler Saw, 1984-1985 (Box 67)
  - Rum and Coke, 1984-1985 (Box 68)
  - Henry IV, Part 1, 1984-1985 (Box 69)
  - A Play of Giants, 1984-1985 (Box 69)
  - Fences, 1984-1985 (Box 70)
  - Talley's Folley, 1984-1985 (Box 70)
  - Stitchers and Starlight Talkers, 1985-1986 (Box 71)
  - A Child's Tale, 1985-1986 (Box 71)
  - The Blood Knot, 1985-1986 (Box 72)
  - Marriage, 1985-1986 (Box 72)
  - Little Eyolf, 1985-1986 (Box 72)
  - Othello, 1985-1986 (Box 72)
  - Crazy From the Heart, 1985-1986 (Box 73)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1985-1986 (Box 74)
  - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1985-1986 (Box 128)
  - Joe Turner's Come and Gone, 1985-1986 (Box 74)
  - Union Boys, 1985-1986 (Box 75)
  - A Walk in the Woods, 1986-1987 (Box 76)
  - Exact Change, 1986-1987 (Box 76)
  - Exact Change, 1986-1987 (Box 128)
  - Neapolitan Ghosts, 1986-1987 (Box 77)
  - Almost By Chance a Woman: Elizabeth, 1986-1987 (Box 77)
  - Almost By Chance a Woman: Elizabeth, 1986-1987 (Box 129)
  - A Place With Pigs, 1986-1987 (Box 77)
  - The Virgin Molly, 1986-1987 (Box 77)
  - Apocalyptic Butterflies, 1986-1987 (Box 78)
  - Dominoes, 1986-1987 (Box 78)
  - The Cemetery Club, 1986-1987 (Box 79)
  - The Cemetery Club, 1986-1987 (Box 130)
  - Heartbreak House, 1986-1987 (Box 80)
  - Heartbreak House, 1986-1987 (Box 130)
  - The Winter's Tale, 1986-1987 (Box 80)
  - The Memento, 1986-1987 (Box 81)
  - Sarcophagus, 1987-1988 (Box 81)
  - Neddy, 1987-1988 (Box 82)
  - The Wall of Water, 1987-1988 (Box 82)
  - The My House Play, 1987-1988 (Box 83)
  - The My House Play, 1987-1988 (Box 131)
  - The Miser, 1987-1988 (Box 83)
  - The Miser, 1987-1988 (Box 131)
  - Ah, Wilderness!, 1987-1988 (Box 84)
  - Long Day's Journey Into Night, 1987-1988 (Box 84)
  - Melons, 1987-1988 (Box 85)
  - Melons, 1987-1988 (Box 132)
  - Chute Roosters, 1987-1988 (Box 85)
  - Chute Roosters, 1987-1988 (Box 132)
  - The Piano Lesson, 1987-1988 (Box 86)
  - Cobb, 1988-1989 (Box 86)
  - Starting Monday, 1988-1989 (Box 87)
  - Starting Monday, 1988-1989 (Box 133)
  - Phaedra and Hippolytus, 1988-1989 (Box 87)
  - Phaedra and Hippolytus, 1988-1989 (Box 134)
  - The Beach, 1988-1989 (Box 88)
  - Moon Over Miami, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
  - The Alchemist, 1988-1989 (Box 90)
  - Playboy of the West Indies, 1988-1989 (Box 90)
  - Playboy of the West Indies, 1988-1989 (Box 134)
  - Kiss of the Spider Woman, 1988-1989 (Box 91)
  - Intermezzo, 1988-1989 (Box 91)
  - Intermezzo, 1988-1989 (Box 135)
  - Interrogating the Nude, 1988-1989 (Box 92)
  - Interrogating the Nude, 1988-1989 (Box 135)
  - Daylight in Exile, 1989-1990 (Box 92)
  - Daylight in Exile, 1989-1990 (Box 136)
  - Pill Hill, 1989-1990 (Box 93)
  - Pill Hill, 1989-1990 (Box 136)
  - Troilus and Cressida, 1989-1990 (Box 93)
  - Pygmalion, 1989-1990 (Box 93)
  - Rust and Ruin, 1989-1990 (Box 94)
  - Miss Julie, 1989-1990 (Box 94)
  - The Solid Gold Cadillac, 1989-1990 (Box 94)
  - Summer and Smoke, 1989-1990 (Box 95)
  - Two Trains Running, 1989-1990 (Box 95)
  - Dinosaurs, 1989-1990 (Box 95)
  - Ties That Bind, 1990-1991 (Box 96)
  - Ivanov, 1990-1991 (Box 96)
  - Bricklayers, 1990-1991 (Box 96)
  - The Size of the World, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
  - Largo Desolato, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
  - Ohio State Murders, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
  - Search and Destroy, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
  - Search and Destroy, 1990-1991 (Box 137)
  - Scapin, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
  - Moon for the Misbegotten, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
  - Underground, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
  - Democracy in America, 1991-1992 (Box 99)
  - Fefu and Her Friends, 1991-1992 (Box 99)
  - My Children! My Africa!, 1991-1992 (Box 99)
  - Edward the Second, 1991-1992 (Box 99)
  - On the Verge, or, The Geography of Yearning, 1991-1992 (Box 100)
  - The Death of the Last Black Man in the Whole Entire World, 1991-1992 (Box 100)
  - The Beauty Part, 1991-1992 (Box 100)
  - St. Joan of the Stockyards, 1992-1993 (Box 101)
  - Hamlet, 1992-1993 (Box 101)
  - The Baltimore Waltz, 1992-1993 (Box 101)
  - Escape from Happiness, 1992-1993 (Box 101)
  - The Colored Museum, 1992-1993 (Box 101)
  - The Green Bird, 1993-1994 (Box 102)
  - Oleanna, 1993-1994 (Box 102)
  - The School for Wives, 1993-1994 (Box 102)
  - The America Play, 1993-1994 (Box 102)
  - As You Like It, 1993-1994 (Box 102)
  - Uncle Vanya, 1994-1995 (Box 103)
  - Antigone in New York, 1994-1995 (Box 103)
  - Figaro/Figaro, 1994-1995 (Box 103)
  - Slavs!, 1994-1995 (Box 104)
  - Le Bourgeois Avant-Garde, 1994-1995 (Box 104)
  - Twelfth Night, 1994-1995 (Box 104)
  - Pentecost, 1995-1996 (Box 104)
  - The Beaux Stratagem, 1995-1996 (Box 105)
  - Landscape of the Body, 1995-1996 (Box 105)
  - Venus, 1995-1996 (Box 105)
  - Mrs. Warren's Profession, 1995-1996 (Box 105)
  - The Reckless Ruthless Brutal Change of It, 1996-1997 (Box 106)
  - My Life on the Moon, 1996-1997 (Box 106)
  - First Lady, 1996-1997 (Box 106)
  - Thunder Knocking on the Door, 1996-1997 (Box 106)
  - The Adventures of Amy Bock, 1996-1997 (Box 106)
  - The Cryptogram, 1996-1997 (Box 107)
  - The Triumph of Love, 1996-1997 (Box 107)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, 1996-1997 (Box 107)
  - Petersburg, 1997-1998 (Box 107)
  - Splash Hatch on the E Going Down, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - Gum, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - The Cure at Troy, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - According to What, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - Candida, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
  - Galileo, 1998-1999 (Box 108)
  - Hay Fever, 1998-1999 (Box 109)
  - Crumbs From the Table of Joy, 1998-1999 (Box 109)
  - Measure for Measure, 1998-1999 (Box 109)
  - The Glass Menagerie, 1998-1999 (Box 109)
  - Imaginary Invalid, 1999-2000 (Box 110)
  - Betrayal, 1999-2000 (Box 110)
  - Richard III, 1999-2000 (Box 110)
  - Curse of the Starving Class, 1999-2000 (Box 110)
  - A Cup of Coffee, 1999-2000 (Box 111)
  - The Birds, 2000-2001 (Box 111)
  - The Way of the World, 2000-2001 (Box 111)
  - Rice Boy, 2000-2001 (Box 111)
  - Big Night, 2000-2001 (Box 111)
  - Heaven, 2000-2001 (Box 112)
  - Serious Money, 2001-2002 (Box 112)
  - Betty's Summer Vacation, 2001-2002 (Box 112)
  - Iphigenia At Aulis, 2001-2002 (Box 112)
  - It Pays to Advertise, 2001-2002 (Box 112)
  - You Never Can Tell, 2001-2002 (Box 113)
  - Kingdom of Earth, 2001-2002 (Box 113)
  - Breath, Boom, 2002-2003 (Box 113)
  - The Psychic Life of Savages, 2002-2003 (Box 113)
  - Fighting Words, 2002-2003 (Box 113)
  - The Black Monk, 2002-2003 (Box 114)
  - Medea/Macbeth/Cinderella, 2002-2003 (Box 114)
  - The Taming of the Shrew, 2002-2003 (Box 114)
  - The Mystery Plays, 2003-2004 (Box 115)
  - The Black Dahlia, 2003-2004 (Box 115)
  - The King Stag, 2003-2004 (Box 115)
  - Culture Clash in America, 2003-2004 (Box 115)
  - King Lear, 2003-2004 (Box 115)
  - The Ladies of the Camelias, 2004-2005 (Box 116)
  - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow, 2004-2005 (Box 116)
  - The Clean House, 2004-2005 (Box 116)
  - The Comedy of Errors, 2004-2005 (Box 117)
  - Miss Julie, 2004-2005 (Box 117)
  - Radio Golf, 2004-2005 (Box 117)
  - The People Next Door, 2005-2006 (Box 117)
  - The Cherry Orchard, 2005-2006 (Box 117)
  - Safe in Hell, 2005-2006 (Box 118)
  - dance of the holy ghosts, 2005-2006 (Box 118)
  - Brundibar/Comedy on the Bridge, 2005-2006 (Box 118)
  - All's Well That Ends Well, 2005-2006 (Box 119)
  - Black Snow, 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - In the Continuum, 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - The Mistakes Madeline Made, 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - The Unmentionables, 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - Eurydice, 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - Lulu, 2006-2007 (Box 120)
  - The Evildoers, 2007-2008 (Box 120)
  - Trouble in Mind, 2007-2008 (Box 120)
  - Tartuffe, 2007-2008 (Box 120)
  - Boleros for the Disenchanted, 2007-2008 (Box 120)
  - Richard II, 2007-2008 (Box 121)
  - A Woman of No Importance, 2007-2008 (Box 121)
  - Happy Now?, 2008-2009 (Box 121)
  - Notes From Underground, 2008-2009 (Box 121)
  - Death of a Salesman, 2008-2009 (Box 121)
  - Passion Play, 2008-2009 (Box 122)
  - Lydia, 2008-2009 (Box 122)
  - Rough Crossing, 2008-2009 (Box 122)
  - Dracula (Yale Rep Story Theatre), undated (Box 122)
  - The Monkey of the Mind (Yale Story Theatre), undated (Box 122)